<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric M. Metodiev on Eric M. Metodiev</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eric M. Metodiev on Eric M. Metodiev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2019</title>
      <link>/publication/2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniFold: A Method to Simultaneously Unfold All Observables</title>
      <link>/publication/omnifold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/omnifold/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Multiparticle Correlators Down to Size</title>
      <link>/publication/multiparticlecorrelators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/multiparticlecorrelators/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures with Public Collider Data</title>
      <link>/post/cmsopendata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cmsopendata/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cms-open-data&#34;&gt;CMS Open Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a historic move, the CMS collaboration publicly released terabytes of their LHC data, available on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://opendata.cern.ch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CERN Open Data Portal&lt;/a&gt;.
Now anyone can play around with real collider data just a few years after it is collected.
This is an amazing step by CMS, guaranteeing that data produced now will be valuable into the far future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore that data.
Using open data in &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1908.08542&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our recent work&lt;/a&gt; has been exciting, educational, and frustrating.
I hope to share some of that with you here.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t a tutorial, but rather a brief tour.
To peer into the open data, you&amp;rsquo;d typically need to install the &lt;a href=&#34;http://opendata.cern.ch/docs/cms-virtual-machine-2010&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CERN virtual machine&lt;/a&gt; or the recently-released &lt;a href=&#34;http://opendata.cern.ch/docs/cms-guide-docker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;docker image&lt;/a&gt; and use the CMS software framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a short cut and dive directly into the data.
We&amp;rsquo;ll do this using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://uproot.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;uproot&lt;/a&gt; python package, which can be easily installed with &lt;code&gt;pip install uproot&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-at-collisions&#34;&gt;Looking at Collisions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;downloading-the-data&#34;&gt;Downloading the Data&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Data Portal has links to many different datasets.
Here we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://opendata.cern.ch/record/21&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jet Primary Dataset&lt;/a&gt;.
This dataset contains events with energetic jets of particles.
We&amp;rsquo;ll see some jets in a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data are stored in &amp;ldquo;Analysis Object Data&amp;rdquo; (AOD) files.
The files have thousands of events each and contain a huge amount of information about every event.
There are almost 5TB of data, so let&amp;rsquo;s keep it simple and focus on one file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download an AOD file by clicking the link below. &lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: 1GB file size.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://opendata.cern.ch/record/21/files/assets/cms/Run2011A/Jet/AOD/12Oct2013-v1/20001/04913DA0-8B3F-E311-924F-0025901AD38A.root&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;04913DA0-8B3F-E311-924F-0025901AD38A.root&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;reading-the-files&#34;&gt;Reading the Files&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see the particles in an event.
We&amp;rsquo;ll use the CMS-constructed &amp;ldquo;particle flow candidates&amp;rdquo; (PFCs) as proxies for the particles that hit the detector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s write a few lines of python to read in the particles from this file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import uproot

# load in the specified file with uproot
file = uproot.open(&#39;04913DA0-8B3F-E311-924F-0025901AD38A.root&#39;)
events = file[b&#39;Events;1&#39;]

# read particle transverse momenta (pts), pseudorapidity (eta), and azimuth (phi)
PFCkey = b&#39;recoPFCandidates_particleFlow__RECO.obj&#39;
pts  = events[PFCkey + b&#39;.pt_&#39;].array()
etas = events[PFCkey + b&#39;.eta_&#39;].array()
phis = events[PFCkey + b&#39;.phi_&#39;].array()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particles are characterized by their energy and direction.
Their energy is quantified by the transverse momentum $p_T$ and their direction is specified by the pseudorapidity-azimuth $(\eta,\phi)$ coordinates of the detector cylinder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;displaying-the-events&#34;&gt;Displaying the Events&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s pick an event (#6457) and actually view it with the following code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import numpy as np
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt

# choose an event
ind = 6457

# plot the collision event of interest
plt.scatter(etas[ind], phis[ind], s=pts[ind], lw=0)

# plot settings
plt.xlim(-5, 5)
plt.ylim(-np.pi, np.pi)
plt.xlabel(&#39;Pseudorapidity $\eta$&#39;)
plt.ylabel(&#39;Azimuthal Angle $\phi$&#39;)
plt.show()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This code produces an &amp;ldquo;unrolled&amp;rdquo; image of the detector cylinder ($\phi$ is periodic).
The event is shown below, depicting higher energy particles as larger dots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./ODexampleevent.png&#34; width=&#34;85%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it! You&amp;rsquo;re looking at the particles produced by a real LHC collision and recorded by the CMS detector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-do-you-see&#34;&gt;What do you see?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two energetic sprays of particles (called jets) that are back-to-back with $\Delta\phi \approx \pi$.
These jets arise from high-energy quarks and gluons, which fragment and hadronize into jets before hitting the detector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AOD file also has information about these jets (and much more!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking closer, we see that the upper jet consists of two energetic prongs.
This is an example of jet substructure.
A lot of recent work has gone into theoretically understanding and experimentally measuring the substructure of jets at the LHC.
More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to play around and look at different events!
See if you can plot different particle types (photons, electrons, hadrons, etc.) as different colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beware&lt;/strong&gt;: Staring at too many event displays may drive you mad. Use caution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-what&#34;&gt;Now what?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;digging-into-details&#34;&gt;Digging into Details&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See any evidence for new physics in the event above? Me neither.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More serious analyses with open data require more work.
First, what event are we even looking at?
If you trust my painstaking byte-by-byte extraction, this code finds the event, run, and luminosity section numbers of an event in this dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import struct

# get the auxiliary event information
aux = events[b&#39;EventAuxiliary&#39;].array(uproot.asdebug)

# get the event, run, and lumiblock numbers from the file bytes
event_num = struct.unpack(&amp;quot;&amp;gt;I&amp;quot;, bytes(aux[ind][43:47]))[0]
run_num   = struct.unpack(&amp;quot;&amp;gt;I&amp;quot;, bytes(aux[ind][35:39]))[0]
lumi_num  = struct.unpack(&amp;quot;&amp;gt;I&amp;quot;, bytes(aux[ind][39:43]))[0]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking at Event 40076805 in Run 166429 and Luminosity Section 54.
This fully specifies the event: it was recorded on Friday, June 3, 2011 at 5:04pm.
The official &lt;a href=&#34;http://opendata.cern.ch/record/1001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CMS list&lt;/a&gt; tells us that this event is considered &amp;ldquo;valid&amp;rdquo; by CMS, with the detector operating as expected. You can find the the &lt;a href=&#34;http://opendata.cern.ch/record/1051&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;time, luminosity&lt;/a&gt;, and other information about the event&amp;rsquo;s luminosity block once you have these numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-bad-news&#34;&gt;The Bad News&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t always avoid using the CMS software framework, at least for now.
There are event and particle properties that require going the traditional route to extract.
Here are some examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Triggers&lt;/strong&gt;: What trigger(s) fired for this event to be stored?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vertexing&lt;/strong&gt;: Which charged particles are from pileup interactions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jet Corrections&lt;/strong&gt;: How much of a jet&amp;rsquo;s energy did the detector collect?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not every usage of the open data will require all of this information, probing the substructure of jets relies heavily on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-good-news&#34;&gt;The Good News&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve done all this hard work for you &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1908.08542&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in our paper&lt;/a&gt;!
We store all the particles within high energy jets from this dataset, making use of this additional information to mitigate pileup and detector effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3340205&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;publicly released&lt;/a&gt; the processed data, plus we did cool physics with it!
I hope that this dataset is broadly useful for anyone who wants to study jet substructure in the CMS Open Data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/9E36IRzUNp?amp=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this demo&lt;/a&gt; that runs right in your browser!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Collider Classifiers on Real Data</title>
      <link>/post/trainondata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/trainondata/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification-at-colliders&#34;&gt;Classification at Colliders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of recent interest in applying classification techniques from machine learning to particle physics.
Methods from &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1511.05190&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;image recognition&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1702.00748&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;natural language processing&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.05165&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;point cloud identification&lt;/a&gt; have outperformed expert-designed algorithms for a variety of collider tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s a problem: collisions at the LHC don&amp;rsquo;t come with labels.
Unlike photos or handwritten digits, you can&amp;rsquo;t recruit an army of volunteers to see whether a Higgs boson was produced (before decaying) in a collision.
All you have is the complicated mozaic of particles that ultimately hits the detector.
So then how do you get labeled training data to feed your classifiers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particle physics, this problem is dodged by relying heavily on simulated events for labels.
You can peer into the inner workings of the simulation and see what particles were produced in the collision.
While these simulations are excellent, they can badly mismodel the subtle correlations among the thousands of particles in a collision event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliance on simulation is troubling for machine learning in particle physics, as models can learn these mismodeled details.
There&amp;rsquo;s no substitute for real data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss our work on overcoming the need for simulation and training classifiers directly on real collider data.
It&amp;rsquo;s a simple and fun story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;training-on-data&#34;&gt;Training on Data?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get right to the key ideas. As I mentioned, they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-the-likelihood-ratio-as-the-optimal-classifier&#34;&gt;1. The Likelihood Ratio as the Optimal Classifier&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you want to classify category $A$ from category $B$ using features ${\bf x}$.
We know, thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neyman%E2%80%93Pearson_lemma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Neyman and Pearson&lt;/a&gt;, that the optimal classifier to do the job is the likelihood ratio:
$$ L_{A/B}({\bf x}) = p_A({\bf x})/p_B({\bf x}),$$
where $p_A({\bf x})$ and $p_B({\bf x})$ are the probability densities of ${\bf x}$ in the two categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $A$/$B$ likelihood ratio (or anything monotonically related to it!) is what we&amp;rsquo;re after if we want a great classifier.
If we had labels for our data, we could train any classifier in the usual way to get an approximation of the likelihood ratio.
But in particle physics, we just don&amp;rsquo;t have those labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-collider-data-as-statistical-mixtures&#34;&gt;2. Collider Data as Statistical Mixtures&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, what we can often measure at colliders are statistical mixtures of the two classes with some fraction $f$.
We can write this mathematically as:
$$ p_{M}({\bf x}) = f p_A({\bf x}) + (1-f) p_B({\bf x}). $$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By slicing and dicing our data in different ways, we can get different mixtures with different fractions.
For example, consider classifying collision debris (jets) from high-energy quarks versus gluons.
As quarks are electrically charged, they are more likely to be produced together with an energetic photon.
Looking for this photon gives you a mixture with a higher fraction of quarks than gluons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s see what the optimal classifier is to classify one mixture from another.
Again, it&amp;rsquo;s simply the likelihood ratio of the two mixtures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ L_{M_1/M_2}({\bf x})  = \frac{f_1 p_A({\bf x}) + (1-f_1) p_B({\bf x})}{f_2 p_A({\bf x}) + (1-f_2) p_B({\bf x})} = \frac{f_1 L_{A/B}({\bf x})  + (1-f_1)}{f_2 L_{A/B}({\bf x}) + (1-f_2)}.$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is monotonically related to $L_{A/B}({\bf x})$, and so it defines the same classifier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words: train a classifier to tell apart the two mixtures and you&amp;rsquo;ll get a great classifier for the underlying categories.
By using the mixtures, you don&amp;rsquo;t need the underlying labels!
You don&amp;rsquo;t even need to know the mixture fractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-classifying-mixtures-as-classifying-categories&#34;&gt;3. Classifying Mixtures as Classifying Categories&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s summarize what we learned as a theorem. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the funny name later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Koala Theorem&lt;/strong&gt;: The optimal classifier between two different mixtures of categories $A$ and $B$ is also the optimal classifier between $A$ and $B$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This result is pretty intuitive.
Say you have two baskets of exotic fruits: one is more rich in &lt;code&gt;foos&lt;/code&gt; and the other in &lt;code&gt;bars&lt;/code&gt;.
Your best guess of which basket a fruit came from is simply your best guess of whether it is a &lt;code&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt; or a &lt;code&gt;bar&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This simple idea has also &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1303.1208&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;appeared previously&lt;/a&gt; for learning from noisy labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification-without-labels&#34;&gt;Classification Without Labels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.02949&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;classification without labels&lt;/a&gt; or CWoLa (&amp;ldquo;koala&amp;rdquo;, as in the furry marsupial) technique for training on real data is based directly on this idea.
Simply slice and dice your data into several mixtures, and train a classifier to tell them apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a cartoon of a koala learning to tell apart signal $S$ from background $B$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./cartooncwola.png&#34; width=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The koala, even with its &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Koala#Description&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;notoriously tiny brain&lt;/a&gt;, learns how to classify the two categories simply by being trained to classify the mixtures from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are assumptions for CWoLa to work, and it&amp;rsquo;s worth spelling them out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Different Fractions&lt;/strong&gt;: The two mixtures have different fractions, $f_1\neq f_2$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample Independence&lt;/strong&gt;: Category $A$ is identical in the mixtures. Same for $B$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first point says that you can&amp;rsquo;t just randomly split your data in half.
The second point says that the slicing and dicing shouldn&amp;rsquo;t affect the distribution of features ${\bf x}$ in categories $A$ and $B$.
In our &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.02949&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1801.10158&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;papers&lt;/a&gt;, we make concrete proposals for ways to meet these requirements in cases of interest, but that&amp;rsquo;s all there is to this idea for training classifiers on collider data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our method was recently applied to real data &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.05306&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;by the CMS collaboration&lt;/a&gt; for their measurement of the $t\bar tb\bar b$ cross section.
By applying CWoLa (&amp;ldquo;training a koala&amp;rdquo;?) in an interesting way, they trained a boosted decision tree (BDT) to classify $t\bar t b \bar b$ events (with two top and two bottom quarks) from the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./cmscwola.png&#34; width=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;To my knowledge, this is the first classifier trained directly on real LHC data!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory of Quark vs. Gluon Discrimination</title>
      <link>/publication/qgpowercounting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/qgpowercounting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Space of Jets with CMS Open Data</title>
      <link>/publication/cmsopendataemd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cmsopendataemd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Machine Learning Landscape of Top Taggers</title>
      <link>/publication/toptagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/toptagging/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Metric Space of Collider Events</title>
      <link>/publication/earthmoverdistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/earthmoverdistance/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Flow Networks: Deep Sets for Particle Jets</title>
      <link>/publication/energyflownetworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/energyflownetworks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018</title>
      <link>/publication/2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data ex Machina: Machine Learning with Jets in CMS Open Data</title>
      <link>/talk/mlforjets2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/mlforjets2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling Jet Categories at Colliders</title>
      <link>/talk/mlforjets2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/mlforjets2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An operational definition of quark and gluon jets</title>
      <link>/publication/defineqg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/defineqg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to classify from impure samples with high-dimensional data</title>
      <link>/publication/weaksupervision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/weaksupervision/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
